A Calendar of The Jefferson Papers of the University of Virginia
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series I: Dated Materials
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to BEVERLEY RANDOLPH., 1791 May 1.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397. Printed: B of R VI 380 (MS. in DLC).
    Introducing Mr. Cassinove of Amsterdam. Asks that he show Tuckahoe to him.
    [260]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to MR. FULWAR SKIPWITH., 1791 May 6.; L. 5 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    John Wayles' responsibility in case of Guineaman. Effect of death of Col. Randolph. Obligation of Farrell and Jones in slave trade with Africa. Cites Freeman 344, Tutthill vs. Roberts. Mentions Mrs. Skipwith's trip to Sweet Springs.
    [2478]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON to [HENRY REMSON]., [1791, May 6]; ALS. Letterpress copy. Fragment. 1 pp.; Barrow. Last page only. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Mr. Wythe too dear a friend to be impartial judge in a matter involving T. J. Returns to Virginia in fall.
    [3126]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to PETER CARR., 1791 May 8.; ALS. 2 pp. Carr-Cary Papers, #1231. Another MS. in MHi.
    Advice on reading and practice of law. Dabney Carr's progress. Delay in payment of Carr's debts at Williamsburg. Payment of Mr. Wayles' debts has crippled his funds. References to Nicholas Lewis and Dr. Thomas Walker.
    [261]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to MARIA JEFFERSON., 1791 May 8.; ALS. 1 pp.; Barrow. Letterpress copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533. Printed: SNR, 164-65.
    Sends nankeen care of Mr. Brown, Richmond. Will answer Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr.'s letters to Monticello before joining James Madison in New York. Travel route: New York to Albany and Lake George, to Bennington, through Vermont to Connecticut River, thence to Hartford and New Haven and to New York and Philadelphia. Maria's riding lessons. Mentions Anne Cary Randolph.
    [2479]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to MARTHA JEFFERSON RANDOLPH., 1791 May 8.; L. 2 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397. MS. in MHi. Printed: Randall II 9 (extract); SNR 199 (extract).
    Importance of good relations with her neighbors. Loss of his vis-a-vis (carriage) in shipment; possible loss of tobacco and John Eppes' books and baggage on Captain Stratton's ship. List of books and furniture to be sent to Monticello. Petit has agreed to come from France as T. J.'s housekeeper. Mentions Thomas Mann Randolph.
    [262]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to GEORGE WASHINGTON., 1791 May 8.; L. 5 pp. #38-414-a. Copied for N. P. Trist ca. 1830. Printed: Ford V 328-330; L & B VIII 192-195. THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to BENJAMIN VAUGHAN. 1791 MAY 11. L. on pp. 3-5. #38-414-a. Copied for N. P. Trist ca. 1830. Letterpress copy in DLC. Printed: Ford V 332-334.
    Washington letter: Indiscretion of J. B. Smith's brother in printing T. J.'s note in approbation of Tom Paine's Rights of Man has caused a split with John Adams. Accounts in Fenno's papers. Discourse on Davila. Plan to replace public records of Virginia burned by the British. Asks permission to copy his letters to Washington written while governor of Virginia.
    [263]
    Vaughan letter: Experiments with mountain rice from Africa and Timor. Thanks for Sacontalá and for Smeaton's book. Astonishment at Burke's Reflections on the French Revolution. Paine's answer. Satisfaction with the new Constitution. Greetings to Lord Wycombe and Dr. Price. Mentions Dr. Priestley.
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to THOMAS LIEPER., 1791 May 10.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Requests payment for Bedford tobacco arrived on Captain Stratton's ship. Painters should start work Monday.
    [264]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to JAMES LYLE., 1791 May 11.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Offers bonds backed by mortgages on land sold to Mr. Ronald in payment for his debts to Lyle, to Kippen & Co. and to Farrell & Jones. Mentions [Alexander] McCaul.
    [265]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to BENJAMIN VAUGHAN., 1791 May 11.; L. 1 pp. #38-414-a. Extract by N. P. Trist ca. 1830. Letterpress copy in DLC. Printed: Ford V 332-334.
    Experiments with mountain rice from Africa and Timor. Thanks for Sacontalá and for Smeaton's book. Astonishment at Burke's Reflections on the French Revolution. Paine's answer. Satisfaction with the new Constitution. Greetings to Lord Wycombe and Dr. Price. Mentions Dr. Priestley.
    [266]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to JAMES MAURY., 1791 May 13.; L. 1 pp. #38-414-a. Extract by N. P. Trist ca. 1830. Printed: B of R VI 318 (MS. in DLC).
    Prosperity of the Union.
    [267]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to FRANCIS EPPES., 1791 May 15.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533. Printed: SNR, 165-66.
    John Wayles Eppes and Capt. Stratton arrived. Letter to Mr. Fulwar Skipwith concerning Guineaman. Coming to Virginia, perhaps not Richmond. John Wayles Eppes's studies. Trip to Lake George, Lake Champlain.
    [2480]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to ELIZABETH WAYLES EPPES., 1791 May 15.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533. Printed SNR, 166.
    Favor from John Wayles Eppes. Letter, this date, to Francis Eppes. Mentions Anne Cary Randolph. Would have left Maria with Mrs. Eppes, but Martha needed her at Monticello.
    [2481]
  - MARTHA JEFFERSON RANDOLPH, Monticello, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1791 May 23.; ALS. 1 pp.; Barrow. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Farming notes from Monticello: strawberries, cherries, beans, inoculation of trees by Anthony. Irregularity of the postal service.
    [268]
  - MARIA JEFFERSON, Monticello, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia., 1791 May 29.; AL. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Thanks for a veil he sent. Study of botany and arithmetic. Her mare is pretty. Abundance of fruit. Mentions Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr., and Anne Randolph.
    [269]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Lake Champlain, to MARTHA JEFFERSON RANDOLPH., 1791 May 31.; L. 2 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397. Printed: Ford V 337-338; SNR 201-202.
    Beauty of Lake George; Lake Champlain less attractive. Trip through New England and New York to Philadelphia. Superior climate of Virginia. Good wishes to Anne.
    [270]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to MARTHA JEFFERSON RANDOLPH., 1791 June 23.; L. 2 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397. Printed: Randall II 21-22; SNR 203-204.
    Headaches gone. Uncertain when he will return to Monticello. Duke of Dorset's daughter complains that Martha has not written. Mentions Fulwar Skipwith, Mrs. Trist, and Mrs. Waters. Asks that tobacco be sent so that he may make payment to John Hanson. Mirabeau and Duke de Richelieu are dead and Duke de Fronsac is head of the family. Mentions Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr., Maria Jefferson, and Anne Randolph.
    [271]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to MARIA JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1791 June 26.; ALS. 1 pp.; Barrow. #501. Draft in MHi. Printed: Randall II 22; SNR 204.
    Geography of Lake George area. Received tobacco reports from Mr. Nicholas Lewis and Mr. Daniel Hylton. Mentions Martha, Anne Cary Randolph, and Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr.
    [272]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to MARIA JEFFERSON., 1791 June 26.; ALS. 1 pp.; Barrow. Letterpress copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533. Printed: SNR, 169.
    Geography of Lake George area. Received tobacco reports from Mr. Lewis and Mr. Hylton. Mentions Martha, Anne Cary Randolph, and Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr.
    [2482]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to JOHN DOBSON., 1791 July 4.; L. 2 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397. MS. in CsmH.
    T. J.'s tobacco will not produce the expected payment on bonds assigned to Dobson by John Hanson, T. J.'s portion of the John Wayles estate debt to Farrell & Jones.
    [273]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to MARTHA JEFFERSON RANDOLPH, [Monticello]., 1791 July 10.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397. MS. in MHi.
    Postal route from Richmond to Staunton via Tuckahoe, Goochland Courthouse, Columbia, and Charlottesville. Stores for Monticello sent by Captain Stratton. Messages for Maria Jefferson, Anne Randolph, and Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr.
    [274]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to [NATHANIEL] CHIPMAN., 1791 July 14.; ALS. 1 pp. Photostat. Original owned by Victor B. Levit. #8265-b.
    Commission as judge of District of Vermont sent at same time as those for attorney and marshal. Encloses a new commission signed by Washington.
    [2482-a]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to [THOMAS MANN RANDOLPH, JR., Monticello]., 1791 July 17.; L. 1 pp. Fragment. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Sugar maple trees from Prince on Long Island. Conversion from tobacco to wheat. Sale of tobacco crop. Stores for Monticello sent by Captain Stratton. Delay in return to Monticello.
    [275]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to JOHN DOBSON., 1791 July 24.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Deficiency in payment of his debts from proceeds of his tobacco crop will be made up by the wheat crop.
    [276]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to MARTHA JEFFERSON RANDOLPH, [Monticello]., 1791 July 24.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397. MS. in MHi.
    Arrival of Petit from France. News of the Convent of Panthemont which Martha attended. Stores for Monticello sent by Captain Stratton. President is ill. News of Mme. de Taubenheim, Botitorer, and William Short.
    [277]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to THOMAS MANN RANDOLPH, JR., [Monticello]., 1791 July 24.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397. MS. in CsmH.
    Proposes to build and rent a mill to Mr. Divers and others. Letters for P. Marks and [Justin P. P.] de Rieux. Mentions Mr. Henderson.
    [278]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to NATHANIEL COLLEY., 1791 July 31.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Receipt of tables.
    [279]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to MARIA JEFFERSON, [Monticello]., 1791 July 31.; ALS. 1 pp. McGregor Library, #1223. Printed: Randall II 22; SNR 204-205.
    Wants stores sent to Mr. Brown, Richmond, moved to Monticello. Sent commodes and chessmen. Petit says chessmen were sent. Asks about Maria's and Martha's music.
    [280]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to MARIA JEFFERSON., 1791 July 31.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533. Printed: SNR, 169-70.
    [2483]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to NATHANIEL BURWELL., 1791 August 1.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Requests information on the public certificates owned by {John?] Paradise which can be used to pay off his debts.
    [281]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to [PHILIP MAZZEI]., 1791 August 2.; L. 3 pp.; Barrow. Letterpress copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Dohrman's, Blair's, Bowdoin's, and George Nicholas, debts to Mazzei. Encloses copies of papers given to T. J. when he departed to Paris. Advises that he turn Virginia certificates into U. S. paper, and consult Edmund Randolph about it. Disapproves of the assumption of state paper at discount. Sale of Colle. Value of Mazzei's land in Richmond. Will take books in payment of Barrois, debt. Glad Mazzei is under the wings of the Diet and King. Distaste for his office. News of Maria Jefferson and Martha Randolph. Greetings to Duchess of Danville and Duke and Duchess de la Rochefoucault. Mentions Foster Debbs and Mr. Garth.
    [282]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to FRANCIS EPPES., 1791 August 7.; ALS. 1 pp. Fragment. Letterpress copy. 1st page only: 2nd page missing. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    See item 2485.
    [2484]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to FRANCIS EPPES., 1791 August 7.; L. 2 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Asks about Capt. Hylton's debts to Mazzei. John Wayles Eppes's law studies. Unsettled time of George Washington's trip to Virginia makes T. J.'s trip uncertain. Hopes to see Mr. and Mrs. Eppes at Monticello because cannot get to Eppington. Tobacco unprofitable. Will sell property to settle debt to John Hanson. Mentions friends at Hors-du-monde.
    [2485]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to THOMAS MANN RANDOLPH, JR., [Monticello]., 1791 August 7.; ALS. 2 pp. Photostat, #2873. Original owned by Harold Jefferson Coolidge.
    August Davies, proposed postal route from Richmond through Columbia and Charlottesville to Staunton Washington's illness. Need for replacing a carriage horse. England's preparation for war. Revolution in Santo Domingo. Estimates census will total 3,800,000 inhabitants.
    [283]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to CHRISTIAN BAEHR., 1791 August 14.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Order for coat and breeches.
    [284]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to COLONEL FORREST, [Georgetown]., 1791 August 14.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Introducing Tench Coxe.
    [285]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to MARTHA JEFFERSON RANDOLPH, [Monticello]., 1791 August 14.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Return to Monticello in September. Stores sent by Captain Stratton. Mentions Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr., Maria Jefferson, and Anne Randolph.
    [286]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to [BENJAMIN] STODDERT., 1791 August 14.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    [287]
  - JOHN GARLAND JEFFERSON to THOMAS JEFFERSON., [1791] August 20 [date received].; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Carr-Cary Papers, #1231.
    Report on law reading. Requests permission to return to Albemarle where he can get books more easily and counteract bad opinion of him there. Reference to his uncle John Garland.
    [595]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to MARIA JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1791 August 21.; ALS. 2 pp.; Barrow. #501. Printed: Randall II 23; SNR 205-206.
    Date for return to Monticello. Purchase of horse for T. J. by Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr. Reference to James Madison.
    [288]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to MARIA JEFFERSON., 1791 August 21.; ALS. 1 pp.; Barrow. Letterpress copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533. Printed: SNR, 170.
    Coming to Monticello. Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr. will get him a new horse. James Madison lends horse for trip to Virginia. Mentions Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr., Martha, and Anne Cary Randolph.
    [2486]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to MARIA JEFFERSON., 1791 August 21.; L. 1 pp. 19th century. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    copy. Duplicates item 2486.
    [2487]
  - THOMAS MANN RANDOLPH, JR., Tuckahoe, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1791 August 22.; ALS. 2 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Visit to Tuckahoe to vote for his father for a seat in the Virginia Senate. Purchase of Edgehill. Papers relating to the legacy left to M. de Rieux. Stoves at Mr. Brown's. T. J.'s return to Monticello. Mentions Martha Randolph.
    [289]
  - WILLIAM TATHAM to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1791 August 26.; ALS. 10 pp.; Barrow. Endorsed by T. J. #9511-c. Printed: Ford-Bixby 49-56.
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to THOMAS MANN RANDOLPH, JR., 1791 August 28.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397. MS. in MHi.
    [Justin P. P.] de Rieux's letters and power-of-attorney. Will meet Commissioners of Public Buildings in Georgetown; then to Orange with James Madison. Requests two wagon horses to meet him. King of France attempts to escape.
    [290]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON Philadelphia, to CHRISTIAN BAEHR., 1791 August 29.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Order for gilet and breeches.
    [291]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to JAMES BROWN, Richmond., 1791 August 29.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397. MS. in MHi.
    Shipment of putty for Monticello by the Sloop Polly.
    [292]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to [JAMES] CURRIE., 1791 August 30.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Mr. Morris' bonds are to serve as security for his debt to Dr. Currie after Dr. Griffin has been satisfied.
    [293]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to JAMES MAURY, Liverpool, England., 1791 August 30.; ALS. 1 pp. Photostat, #931. Endorsed by T. J. Deposited by Mrs. Anne F. Maury. Printed: B of R VI 318 (MS. in DLC).
    Acknowledges receipt of copy of the Corn Law. Refusal of ship masters to render accounts. Crop of wheat is fine, but corn and tobacco have been hurt by a drought.
    [294]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to THOMAS LIEPER., 1791 August 31.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Requests note for fifty or one hundred dollars. Shipment of tobacco expected on Captain Stratton's ship.
    [295]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to THOMAS LIEPER., 1791 August 31.; ALS. 1 pp.; Barrow. Letterpress copy. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Money for trip. Shipment of tobacco expected on Capt. Stratton's ship.
    [2488]
  - FRANCIS EPPES, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia., 1791 September 2.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Mazzei's claims against Captain Hylton's estate will be referred to Ralph Hylton. Betsy [Elizabeth Eppes?] has another girl. Invitation to T. J., the Randolphs, and Maria Jefferson to come to Eppington. Education of John Wayles Eppes.
    [296]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to ANDREW ELLICOT., 1791 September 15.; L. 2 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Offer to hire Mr. Shuter's houseboy, Billy.
    [297]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to ADAM LINDSAY., 1791 September 15.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Order for myrtle wax candles and Hughes [Hewes] crab cider.
    [298]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JAMES LYLE., 1791 September 15.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397. MS. in CsmH.
    Requests account of Peter Jefferson's estate, necessary for settlement of Dr. Walker's account. Will make payment upon the sale of his tobacco. Mentions John Nicholas.
    [299]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JAMES WILSON., 1791 September 21.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Requesting that he come to Monticello to make a settlement with T. J. Mentions Nicholas Lewis.
    [300]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JAMES BROWN, Richmond., 1791 September 27.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Requests list of tobacco sold to Mr. Donald. Order for muslin, dimity, and shoes for Maria Jefferson, and cash for his return to Philadelphia. Discusses various methods of payment.
    [301]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to FRANCIS EPPES., 1791 October 5.; L. 2 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    To Philadelphia with Maria. To Virginia in Spring to settle with John Hanson. Cannot find Mazzei's account against Hylton. Perhaps with Blair. Samuel Woodson and Robert Lewis defaulted on bond; have not paid Eppes money spent on Maria. To pay John Wayles Eppes. Books from Europe for John Wayles Eppes. Mr. Skipwith says Wigan, Bevin's administrator, sues T. J. and Eppes. Health of Mrs. Eppes.
    [2489]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to HENRY SKIPWITH., 1791 October 5.; L. 9 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397. MS. in CsmH.
    Hopes for an accommodation in the action by Bevins' executor against them. T. J.'s opinion of the paper signed by Skipwith and John Hanson (concerning the Wayles estate). Will not assume responsibility if John Wayles was security for a debt of Benjamin Harrison to Coles. Mentions Eppington, Hors du Monde, Mrs. Skipwith, and Mr. and Mrs. Francis Eppes.
    [302]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to FRANCIS WALKER., 1791 October 6.; ALS. 1 pp. Letterpress copy. Fragment. 1st page only. Barrow. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Mr. Lyle to supply copy of Kippen and Company account with estate of Peter Jefferson prior to first accounts with Mr. Nicholas. Letter from Lyle, Manchester, calls for delay until T. J. returns from Philadelphia. Accounts with Mr. Harvie and Dr. Walker.
    [2490]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JAMES WILSON., 1791 October 6.; L. 2 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Wilson's account with T. J., covering the bonds of Richardson & Scruggs, Austin, James, Carter, and Randolph. Will send an order on Wilson to [John] Dobson for the balance due. Wilson will handle other bonds in the future for T. J.
    [303]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, [Monticello], to NATHANIEL POPE., 1791 October 7.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Order on Pope in favor of Andrew Donald for William and James Donald & Co. to be paid from money collected from Robert Lewis and Samuel Woodson.
    [304]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, [Monticello], to NATHANIEL POPE., 1791 October 7.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Order on Pope in favor of James Strange for Donald Scott & Co., to be paid from collections from Robert Lewis and Samuel Woodson.
    [305]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON to JAMES STRANGE., 1791 October 7.; ALS. 1 pp. Fragment. Letterpress copy. With ANS, Letterpress copy, 1791 October 7, T. J. to N. POPE. Barrow. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Pope to pay note from proceeds of suits in Henrico District Court against Robert Lewis and Samuel Woodson of Goochland. Returns to Philadelphia. Pope to pay Strange or Donald Scott.
    [2491]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to NATHANIEL POPE., 1791 October 7.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Nicholas Lewis has given up the management of T. J.'s affairs. Directions for collection and payment of his debts. Money due from Robert Lewis and Samuel Woodson. Payment due James Strange of Richmond for Donald Scott & Co., to Andrew Donald for William and James Donald & Co., and to [John] Dobson. Stop the suit against Lewis and Ware.
    [306]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to NICHOLAS LEWIS., 1791 October 11.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Payments to [James] Currie, John Dobson, and John Hanson. Loss of tobacco shipped for Tom Cobbs to Mr. Ballow by T. J.'s slave, Phill.
    [307]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON to MARIA JEFFERSON., [1791] October 18.; ALS. 1 pp.; insect damage in lower right. McGregor Library, #1223.
    Instructions regarding her trip to Baltimore and Philadelphia. Mentions Mr. Giles.
    [308]
  - FRANCIS EPPES, Eppington, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1791 October 24.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Elizabeth Eppes' illness. Purchase of donkey from Mrs. Bolling. John Wayles Eppes' expenses. [Henry?] Skipwith's sale [of tobacco?] a good one. Fall in tobacco price. Mentions Nicholas Lewis.
    [309]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to the REV. MATTHEW MAURY., 1791 October 25.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Payment to Maury through his brother at Fredericksburg.
    [310]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to MATTHEW MAURY., 1791 October 25.; ALS. 1 pp. Letterpress copy. Endorsed by T. J. Barrow. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Encloses payment promised in letter from Monticello, in care of Maury's brother, Fredericksburg. Redeemable in U.S. Collector's Office.
    [2492]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to THOMAS MANN RANDOLPH, JR., [Monticello]., 1791 October 25.; L. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397. Printed: SNR 207.